

Robin Baumann Computer Vision Engineer



October 08, 1996



Karlsruhe, Germany



www.robin-baumann.com

About me ——

I received my MSc degree with distinction from Karlsruhe University of Applied Sciences, where I specialized in Machine Learning. I am particularly interested in Computer Vision and its intersection with Computer Graphics. I like to spend my free time doing all kinds of sports. For example, I currently prepare for a triathlon. To expand my knowledge, I read non-fiction books about different topics and enjoy spending time outdoors with my friends. My other passion besides sports is music. As such, I play the Saxophone and enjoy going to concerts and festivals.

Skills -

Python

TensorFlow

Python Scientific Stack

PyTorch

Docker

Git

C++

The skill scale is from 0 (Fundamental Awareness) to 6 (Expert).

Education

2019-2021 Karlsruhe University of Applied Sciences

M.Sc. in Computer Science, Final Grade: 1,2 (GPA equivalent: 4,0)

2015-2018 Baden-Württemberg Cooperative State University

B.Sc. in Computer Science. Final Grade: 1,4 (GPA equivalent: 3,7)

Employment History

2021 - today Data Scientist (80 %)

inovex GmbH

Mostly Computer Vision Projects

• Image recognition and foreground segmentation.

Research Assistant (20 %) Karlsruhe University of Applied Sciences

Continuation of research from Master's thesis

Effects of data deficiency on shape encoding produced by shape autoencoders used in Neural Fields.

2019 - 2021 Working Student

inovex GmbH

Several Deep Learning and Data Science projects.

• Deep Learning for mobile devices with TensorFlow Lite

2018 - 2019 Big Data Scientist

inovex GmbH

Projects in Deep Learning and Data Engineering.

• Point Cloud Classification for iOS Application with TensorFlow

2015 - 2018 Cooperative Student of Computer Science

Circled through many teams in the R&D department.

Projects

2021 Master Thesis inovex GmbH

"Autodecoders for 3D shape completion from deficient 3D input"

Implemented Mesh R-CNN and Pix3D in TensorFlow Graphics.

• Reconstruction of articulated and non-articulated shapes from single-view depth maps using Neural Occupancy Fields.

2020 Google Summer of Code

TensorFlow

Deele deele Theele

Testo Visual Systems GmbH

2018 Bachelor Thesis

"Classification of reconstructed 3D structures based on object

recognition of facade elements in multiple images"

• Integrate Object Detection CNN into Structure from Motion pipeline

• Fuse semantic information from CNN into 3D reconstruction

Interpersonal Skills

I always try to build rapport with my co-workers. I do so by engaging in discussions and offer to stand by for rubber duck debugging. I try to lead by example and am received as a reliable co-worker by my peers. One of my strengths is to stay calm and perform consistently in stressful projects and prior to deadlines.

